### Rishi Bommu

### rishidharreddy.bommu@sjsu.edu

Linkedin- www.linkedin.com/in/RishiBommu

#### Profile:

I am a junior pursuing Computer Science at San Jose State University. I am hard working and love to face a challenge. I am self motivated to succeed and am in pursuit of graduating with a B.S. in just three years. I have a strong foundation in Computer Science from Algorithms to Data Structures. My curiosity in the field drives me to learn more and use the skills I've learned to find the optimal solutions.

#### **Education:**

Ohlone College 2010-2013 Concurrent enrollment San Jose State University- **3.89/4 Major GPA** Expected Graduation Date - **Spring 2016**  Computer Science B.S.- Last Year
Graduating with Honors in three years
Minor In Mathematics
Minor in Humanities

## **Experience:**

## Proofpoint Software Engineer Intern June/2015-August/2015

- Core Foundation building Cassandra Stores using Java, Thrift and REST API
- Experience building Backend Database Reports using Ruby and JavaScript
- Application of Multi-Threaded Concepts (Java) and Singleton Design (Guice injection framework)

# Volkswagen 3D Feature Detection Researcher January/2015- May/2015

- Future of video image processing is ready to be discovered
- Researching various areas of video image detection from Lane Detection, Distance radar, and Night to Day image processing; sponsored by Volkswagen.

# Academic Scheduling- Agile Development Project January/2015- May/2015

- In Depth knowledge of Agile Methodology
- Project to optimize Academic Scheduling forms from physical to digital format.
- Was Spring Leader for Sprint 1 of 5
- Experience working in team projects though usage of Joget Work flow

# Math Origami Research Programmer August/2014- December/2014

- Graduate level Math Research as an Undergraduate
- Research in understanding of folded and connected states in 2D Structures
- Experience in creating programs to replicate Meanders and Folded States
- Found all possible fold possibilities given a vertex with 20 or less edges with proof

# BitCoin Server- Self Built January/2013- May/2013

- Home-Made BitCoin Server to mine bit coins at the optimal speed
- Optimization in CPU vs GPU mining
- Profound skills in working with Linux and Unix

## IOS application Deployment and Publication July/2012- July/2013

- Self-Motivated Project in Summer 2012
- Self Studied Objective-C/C coding and Apple IOS SDK
- Created user UI and application from ground up- Back End and Front End
- Finished Product- Rusher- GPS application that intertwines Internet searching and a GPS
- Published Application with over 2000 downloads

## **Hackathons:**

### Yahoo Hackathon

- Self Healing and Error Management system problem
- Solution proposed in GUI with back end implementation to prioritize errors

## **Cisco Innovation Challenge**

- Challenge to improve education
- Proposed Flipped model in Education system

## Intel Rapid Prototyping Challenge 2 and 3

- Challenge to quickly gather a group of engineers and designers and create a prototype
- Advised and helped organize team to see potential design possibilities

# Non-Technical Experience:

# SJSU Salzburg Global Scholars Conference June/2014

- 2014-2015 Salzburg Scholar for Global Citizenship and change
- Discussed global issues and implementation of global change
- Discussed global citizenship and promotion of unity
- Gained valuable experience perceiving world problems and looking at the world from a global perspective.

# Professional Magician October/2010- Present

- Performed the art of magic for various charity shows and organizations.
- Performed charity shows in India for underprivileged schools
- Performed entertainment for Corporations such as Cisco and Washington Hospital
- Gained valuable business experience in working own business and providing entertainment

### **Known Fundamental Skills**

- Know Agile Development Process
- Object-Oriented Design
- Unix/Linux Utilities and Programming
- Computer Architecture
- Digital Imaging and video editing

### **Honors and Skills**

- SJSU Salzburg Scholar
- Phi Theta Kappa Honors
- CAMCOS Math Scholar
- SJSU Dean's Scholar
- Merit Computer Science Department Scholarship